

Email: sagard147@gmail.com Contact Number: (+91) 8867926919

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sagar-dhage-513250128/

Summary

Dedicated and efficient Software engineer focused on working on scalable high performing solutions with 5+ years of experience working on cloud-based services. I have experience of working on projects from their conception to market release. With an active interest in learning more about whatever I do, I am focused on establishing technical expertise over concepts. I work on following best coding practices and striving for engineering excellence while having a great time with my teammates.

Technical Skills

Languages Java, C#, Python, C, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS

Databases MySQL, MongoDB, CosmosDB

Technologies/Frameworks Git, Bootstrap, Django, Nodejs, ExpressJs, ReactJs, KnockoutJS, AngularJs, Junit, Mocito,

AWS Services (EMR, lambda, s3, EC2), ASP.NET Core, Azure Services

Work Experience

Microsoft, Hyderabad:

Software Engineer II

May 2021 - Present

Enterprise Agreement

Part of Enterprise Commerce team, responsible for enabling and optimizing the end-to-end cost management and billing experience for **30K+** Enterprise Agreements on Azure Cloud.

• EA Partner Onboarding on Azure:

Played a key role in enabling Partner experience on Azure Portal by onboarding essential APIs and creating a user-friendly interface from scratch using KnockoutJS and TypeScript, now actively serving **3K+** partners monthly.

- Analyzed and guided the team in designing the schema and framework for EA partner organization entities, facilitating their migration to the Cosmos platform.
- Designed and implemented the partner role management and authorization API service within billingRp.
- Developed the Partner Access Management Dashboard as the sole fullstack developer, successfully launching the Partner Role Management service for EA customers on Azure.

• Billing Profile Monthly Usage Summary:

- Led the analysis of the existing EA system and devised an optimized approach to develop web APIs for Billing Profile usage information.
- Created the Billing Profile monthly detail summary view, allowing for a detailed breakdown of charges by services and hierarchy. Empowered both partners and customers to comprehend charges in various ways within the Azure portal.
- o Implemented and delivered the Pricesheet export functionality, offering customers the most streamlined experience for exporting pricing information.
- Designed and developed a sync job worker responsible for synchronizing roles from the WEAP SQL system to Cosmos DB, supporting the billingRP (billing Resource Provider) services. Functioned as a fullstack developer to deliver the Notification Contact Management System for EA customers on the Azure portal.
- Developed the Invoice's Items details view and seamlessly integrated it with Azure Portal, providing EA
 customers with comprehensive visibility into their MACC (Microsoft Azure Consumption Commitment) usage
 information.
- Designed and implemented an enhanced user experience feature, "Remember my selection," which simulates the user's previously chosen billing scope for cost management within the enterprise menu, optimizing the experience for EA customers.
- Worked to enable subscription management, billing properties, and policies within the Fairfax cloud environment, facilitating EA customers' smooth transition from the EA Portal to Azure.
- Led and successfully delivered the service hardening initiative across the entire Enterprise codebase, with a strong focus on addressing security and privacy concerns.
- Designed and implemented a pluggable module for REST clients to enforce **AAD/SN+I** (Azure Active Directory/Service Principal + Identity) based authentication. Led the integration of Key Vault with applications to automate certificate rotation, resulting in a zero-touch certificate autorotation system for EA.
- Demonstrated strong problem-solving abilities by efficiently handling on-call responsibilities and collaborating with the team to identify solutions, leading to resolution of all customer-reported issues within 48 hours.
- Exhibited a consistent commitment to operational excellence when handling various ad hoc tasks.

Technologies used: C#, KnockoutJS, TypeScript, Azure Services (Storage, Analytics, DevOps), ASP.NET Core.

Samsung Research Institute, Bangalore:

Senior Software Engineer

Feb 2020 - Mar 2021

Working on **statistical/ML** based approaches to provide useful insights on data obtained from the devices it runs on for diagnostic purposes and feature enhancements.

Diagmon-Analytics

- Worked as a principal developer in developing the below features.
- o Optimized the current runtime of Athena queries via **AWS Firehose integration**.
- Enhanced the server-side logic of a Samsung native application by building appropriate REST APIs using Spring Boot.
- Worked with AWS Lambda and AWS S3 to deploy a scalable, event driven log analysis module to process error logs pertaining to Samsung native applications.

Technologies used: Java, AWS Services (S3, Lambda, Firehouse), Spring Boot.

Velocity-alert

- Velocity Processor:
- Worked as a principal developer in developing a Time Series Anomaly Detection module which uses
 ARIMA (Auto Regressive Integrated Moving Average) technique to infer anomalous data points in the
 daily inflow of error logs in real time. This module has a capacity to process an inflow of 500K logs/day.
- o Implemented Data generation module to fetch the data required from AWS Redshift.
- o Implemented the service to analyze and generate reports for service admin to get the useful insights about the cause of sudden growth in inflow of issues.
- Working as a principal developer to implement the trend forecasting using FBProphet machine learning module for the time series data in admin and service reports.

Technologies used: Python, AWS Redshift.

<u>Software Engineer</u> <u>July 2018 – Feb 2020</u>

SamsungMall

- Developed and delivered the **Keyword classifier service** using **Fasttext** machine learning classification algorithm to detect the category of the searched keyword and call the related third-party API for the service.
- Worked as a principal developer in implementing User Segment feature which helps to categorize the users based on the transactions performed by them in the past and personalizes the homepage of SamsungMall application using curated campaigns.
- Worked as a full stack developer in designing and developing the **Evaluation dashboard** web application to test and visualize the response of all the production APIs which are being used in SamsungMall application.

Technologies used: HTML, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Nodejs, Express, MongoDB.

Search Engine Optimization

The project is about conversion of service application pages into quality webpages dynamically with better SEO score which gives better search ranking

- Worked as a full stack developer in designing and developing the Content Management System
 Dashboard web application for Service Admin to create and audit the components for dynamically generating webpages of service applications.
- Integrated the **Semrush Tool APIs** in dashboard to visualize and monitor the performance of the live Service application's webpages.
- Analyzed and Demonstrated to the Service Admin how dynamic public and private indexing will lead to more daily active users for service application.
- Interacted and the led the Service Admin and Service Developers to gather requirements to develop service
 application's SDK package which will hook the application with dynamically generated public and private
 indexes.
- Implemented the service in the dashboard to create and manage the **Public and Private indexes** of service application.
- Implemented the deferent access roles for service user to provide different set of privileges and services.

Technologies used: React Framework, Nodejs, Express, EC2, S3, Lambda, CloudWatch, MongoDB.

Software Engineer Intern

<u>Jan 2018 – July 2018</u>

SamsungMall

• Worked as a sole developer in designing and developing the pipeline service - **Trending keywords** generator using linear regression machine learning technique which processes the previous days' user

- search transaction logs stored in **AWS S3** and generates the trending keywords and stores in database. This is deployed as **AWS lambda function** which is triggered by **cloudWatch event**
- Implemented the service to email the generated trending keywords and its analysis report to the Service Admin

Technologies used: Nodejs, Express, S3, Lambda, CloudWatch, SES, MongoDB.

INGUIN Technologies, Bangalore:

Software Engineer Intern

June 2017 - July 2017

 Developed APIs for web applications using Django to facilitate booking appointments for doctors, creating invoice lists and prescription forms.

Technologies used: Python, Django

Projects

Identification of Languages in a Multilingual Document:

Image Processing

The project aimed on identifying and separating different language (Kannada, English, Hindi) present in the given document. Based on different properties of each language categorizing the words in each document is done.

Technologies used: Python.

 Publication - A Convolution Neural Networks Based Character and Word Recognition System for Similar Script Languages Kannada and Telugu – Published in Proceedings of ICETIT 2019 Link - https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-030-30577-2_26

Educational Qualification

PES Institute of Technology, Bangalore

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Science CGPA: 9.21/10

August 2014 - May 2018